Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.015
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series IV: Unprocessed Photographs.
  - Subseries IV:B: Individuals in Groups
    - Law, Oliver; Joey Mayer, Schicker, Walt Schuetrum, Max (Mac) Binn, Sterling, Pete Smith, Ray Braden, Jack Hartzman, Ed Balchowsky, Bill Bailey, Jimmy Moon, Eugene Poling, Ken Graeber, Moe Fishman, Milt Wolff, and unidentified individuals (Box 7)
    - Lending, Ed; Bob Steck (Hospital in Madrid) (Box 7)
    - Lending, Ed; Bob Steck, Art Gorgan (nee Goldberg?) - Before embarking (Box 7)
    - Lending, Ed; Douglas Male, Vince Lossowski (Box 7)
    - Lipton, Dave and unidentified man (Box 7)
    - Medical Aid SCW (Box 7)
    - Meunier, Henry; Rubin, Hank (Kneeling) at Chateau Becade, Listrac, Bordeaux (Box 7)
    - Miaja, J. Hernandez, Gral. Rojo, Gral. Hidalgo de Cisnero (Junta de Defensa de Madrid) (Box 7)
    - Miller, Mitchell and Bill Mayer and Negative (Box 7)
    - Morgan, Crawford; Leo Markowitz, Eric DeWitt Parker, and Langston Hughes (Box 7)
    - Mulgrew, Sean; Red Lion (Wedding: Kilburn, London, 1935) with Dolly Flynn, Mrs. Mulgrew, Unidentified, Peter O'Connor, Unidentified, Tommy Patten (Box 7)
    - Negrin (Cortes en Monserrat) (Box 7)
    - Negrin, Martinez Barrios - Castillo de Vich with the leaders and comissars of the International Brigades (Box 7)
    - Negrin, Rojo, Lister, Osorio, Tofall (Poblet) (Box 7)
    - O'Connell, Mrs. Jerry, former Rep O'Connell, Rep. Bernard, Jane Addams - Lift the Embargo Conference (Jan 9, 1939) (Box 7)
    - Parrott, Ursula; Heywood Brown, Quentin Reynolds, David McKelvy White (Box 7)
    - Pasqual, Milt Cohen (Box 7)
    - Pellegrin and Manuel (Orderlies) and Jose (ambulance driver) (Box 7)
    - Post-SCW Interview: David Shriver, Steve Nelson, Morris Stamm, Robert Colodney (June 29, 1973), Jun 29, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Raven, Robert; Albert Robbins, [Marvin Howishan?] (Villa Paz? with Injured Soldiers) (Box 7)
    - Reed, Bob & Antoni Josep Morella Galan (1996) (Box 7)
    - Returning Veterans on the Pres Harding (from Lex Weinerman) (Box 7)
    - Rivera, Dennis; Padrino, Blas (Box 7)
    - Roger, Frank; Jack Cooper, Walter Dicks, Louis Bortz, and others unidentified (V-329) (Box 7)
    - Rubin, Hank and Bernard Ganter of Mumm Champagne (Box 7)
    - Sadin, Sam; Terry Cooper Sadin, Lockey Goldfine, Edna Moskowitz, Dorothy Barocas, Leona Baskin Mancher, Henry Foner, Jeanette Cohen Sutton, Arthur Ledifeustein, Bill Levenson, Al Goldberg (Hollywood Caravan to Spain) (Box 7)
    - Schilling, Nathan and two unidentified individuals (Box 7)
    - Slipyan, Sam; Conlon Nancarrow, Ed Lending, Norman Schmidt (Box 7)
    - Smith, Bill and Unidentified Man (Box 7)
    - Smith, Owen; Vincent Lossowski, Ed Lending, Maurine Hawkins, Peter Frye (Box 7)
    - Smorodin, Abe; Dolores Ibarruri (Post-SCW) (Box 7)
    - Stone, Hy; Mike Feller, Joe Stone, Eli Begleman, Hy Katz (Brunete Campaign), July 1937 (Box 7)
    - Soldiers: Torres, Kudish, Nahunchuk, Van der Schelling, Roech, Dixon, Mohar, Mann, Rigby, Comar, Dorsky, Lavrin, Dailey, Capadena (Box 7)
    - Soldiers [Unidentified] (Box 7)
    - Spanish Government: Negrin, Martinez Barrio, Alvarez del Vayo (Box 7)
    - Suni, Tovio; John Viitaniemi (Jussi Wiitaniemi) in Barcelona, Apr 18, 1938 (Box 7)
    - Taylor, Joe; Sam Weissman, Morris Stamm (Box 7)
    - Theron, M; Hank Rubin (Inspecting grapes at Chateau Becade, Listrac, Bordeaux), Sep 24, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Troxil, Stephen: Cutting Hair (from Dave Smith Collection) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (from Frances Patai, a part of Salaria Kee O'Reilly's Estate) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (mostly post-SCW) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified From SCW (Box 7)
    - Unidentified, on SS Champlain, Le Havre (V-327) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified, on SS Champlain, Le Havre (Boat) (V-328) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (Returning on SS Champlain, Le Havre) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified, on SS President Harding, New York (Boat) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (SCW Photos) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified [Spanish Politicians?] + Negative (Box 7)
    - Unidentified (V-316) (Box 7)
    - Vincent Sheehan, Alvarez Albernoz, Ales Bebler, Heywood Broun, Ursula Parrott, Quentin Reynolds, David McKelvy White, and Others Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Wachtel, Marion [Merriman]; Margaret Nelson, Steve Nelson (Cape Cod), Apr 18, 1980 (Box 7)
    - Weisenfeld, Nathan [and Teddy Pitril?] (Lincoln Battalion XIV Brigade) (Box 7)
    - Whelan, Joe and Louis Figaro (Box 7)
    - White, David McKelvy and Kate Allen (Box 7)
    - Wolff, Milton; Mayor Loni Hancock, Berkeley (Box 7)
    - Wolff, Milton; Vivian Hallaway, Van Berg, Bondes, Sennett, Rolfe, Dardow, Rosner, Lane, Nelson, V. Hallman, Sue Jordan, Barbara Lubin, Ed Asner, Ronald V. Dellums (Box 7)
    - Yardas, Ed; Bob Peters, Jack Neshooly (aboard the S.S. Washington), Mar 19, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Subseries IV:C: Subjects, General
    - Activism (Box 7)
    - Activism (Box 7)
    - Ambulance to Nicaragua and "Close Bases in Spain" Rally (Box 7)
    - Anti-Franco Demonstrations (Box 7)
    - Anti-Franco Demonstrations (Box 7)
    - Anti-US-Franco Bases Pact Rally, Mar 27, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Herman (Gabby) Rosenstein, VALB - Political Prisoners in Spain Demonstration (1968) (Box 7)
    - May Day 1938, Spain: Photos and Leaflets (Box 7)
    - Post-SCW Gatherings, VALB, and Postcards (Box 7)
    - Post-SCW, Rallies, Meetings, and Photos of Dolores Ibarruri (Box 7)
    - Rallies in Spain, [1930s?] (Box 7)
    - Rally, New York City (Box 7)
    - Spanish Aid (photo by Ted Batchelor) (Box 7)
    - Strike: Textile Workers in New Bedford, MA (Box 7)
    - VALB (Box 7)
    - VALB (Box 7)
    - VALB (Box 7)
    - VALB [raining] (Box 7)
    - VALB: Against Fascism in Spain (Box 7)
    - VALB Bay Area Iraq War Protest (from Corinne Thornton) (Box 7)
    - VALB (Negatives and Copies) (Box 7)
    - VALB (New York) (Box 7)
    - VALB (New York) (Box 7)
    - VALB, May Day Parade (Box 7)
    - Village Voice Picket and Reunion (Box 7)
    - War Correspondence, Posters, Negative Copies of Demonstration (Box 7)
    - Aviation/Aviators (Box 7)
    - Aviation/Aviators (Box 7)
    - Aviation/Aviators (Box 7)
    - Battlefront (Box 7)
    - Battlefront (Box 7)
    - Battlefront (Box 7)
    - Battlefront (Box 7)
    - Battlefront: Bilbao, June 1937 (Box 7)
    - Battlefront: Tanks (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: [Abe Osheroff photos?] (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Citizens, Soldiers (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: City, Civilians, Workers, and Wartime Evacuations (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: City, Country-Side, Graveyard, and Couples (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Gatherings, Works and some landscapes (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Spanish Peasants (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Sports, Soldiers, Citizens (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Work (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Work (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Work (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Workers and Peasants (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Workers and Peasants (Box 7)
    - Daily Life: Workers on Factories and Farms (Box 7)
    - Destruction (Box 7)
    - Destruction (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Barcelona, Granollers, Nules, and Guadalajara Prisoner (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Belchite (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Buildings (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Aerial Bombardment (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Guernica and Hospitals (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Nules (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Shown by Evua Polle in the Instituto de Higiene de Alfonso XIII (1925 and 1939) (Box 7)
    - Destruction: Valencia, Nules, Granollers, and Other cities (Box 7)
    - Artwork (Box 8)
    - Balchowsky, Edward: Grave (Box 8)
    - Belchite (Box 8)
    - Church [Moscow?] (Box 8)
    - Corbera del Ebro photos by George and Elinor Haber (Box 8)
    - Cordoba (Box 8)
    - Disassembled SCW Photo Album (Box 8)
    - "Dr. Edward K. Barsky" Ambulance in Nicaragua (Box 8)
    - Education (Box 8)
    - Education (Schools, Libraries, "Cultura") (Box 8)
    - Eider, Louis: Post Spanish Civil War Photographs (Box 8)
    - Eider, Louis: Spanish Civil War Photographs (Box 8)
    - Gandall, William: Memorial Service (Box 8)
    - Harbor Photos (Box 8)
    - Huesca (Box 8)
    - Kozar, John: Photographs of Soldiers, Landscape, and Ambulances (includes self-portrait) (Box 8)
    - Martin Maki Photographs: Family and Soldiers in SCW (Box 8)
    - Medical Personnel (Negative Copies) (Box 8)
    - Meetings during SCW (Negative Copies) (Box 8)
    - Miaja, Ibarruri, Evans, Robeson, [Unidentified Individuals], Ammunition, Cultural Campaign Truck (Box 8)
    - Moe Fishman Photos Sent to the NY Times Book Review (Box 8)
    - Peter Frye Photographs (Box 8)
    - Photographs of Jack Friedman (Box 8)
    - Photographs of Spain and Battlefront (Box 8)
    - Post-SCW Activism: Group Photos (Box 8)
    - Post-SCW Photos (Box 8)
    - Pre-SCW/SCW Photos, Bill Gandall (Box 8)
    - Rappoport, Irving: Photographs (Box 8)
    - Rehabilitation Office of FALB and Negative (Fredericka Martin, Gertrude Nelson) (Box 8)
    - San Miniatol Monte (Church) (Box 8)
    - Scenes of War (Box 8)
    - Smith, David, Photographs: Soldiers (Box 8)
    - Soldiers of the 11th Brigade: Photo Album by Martha Swatosch (Box 8)
    - Spaniards Reading News (Box 8)
    - Spanish Republic Medallion for International Brigades (Box 8)
    - Tank, Plaque (C-778) and War Preparations (Box 8)
    - Town/Village (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Men at Podium (Box 8)
    - Veterans of ALB, Fredericka Martin Interview and Group Photo (Box 8)
    - World War II (Box 8)
    - World War II, Col. James Roosevelt, Col Carlon -- Marine Raider Commanders (San Diego) (Box 8)
    - World War II, Guadalcanal Photos (Box 8)
    - Vineyards of Chateau Becade from Hank Rubin (Box 8)
  - Subseries IV:D: Medical
    - Medical Aid, Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid, Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid, Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: ALBA Ambulance in Nicaragua and Wounded Veterans (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Ambulance Delivered to Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Ambulance Photos (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Ambulance, "To the Defense of Democracy in Spain, donated by The Workers of the Furriers Joint Council of New York" (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: American Aid and International Labor Defense (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: American Relief Ship for Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: British Medical Unit (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Hospital Photos (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Lauser, Manny - American Medical Services (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Lini Fuhr, Headnurse (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Jarama Front Camp Hospital (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Nurses (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Nurses (Negative Copies) (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Nurses (Photos from Patai) (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Spain (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Spanish Civil War Nurses (Box 8)
    - Medical Aid: Third American Medical Unit (Box 8)
  - Subseries IV:E: Memorials, Monuments, Celebrations, Reunions
    - 20th Anniversary Photos sent to Moe Fishman [Negative Copies], Feb 12, 1957 (Box 8)
    - 50th Anniversary Photos by Bob Coane [California] (Box 8)
    - Abe Smorodin, Louis Lefkowitz, Salmon Salzman - 50th Anniversary, (Spain), Nov 1986 (Box 8)
    - ALBA Event (CD included), 30 Apr 2006 (Box 8)
    - ALBA Event (Contact Sheet) (Box 8)
    - Anthony Toney at NY Dinner (Box 8)
    - Bill Bailey (Box 8)
    - City College Memorial Plaque (Box 8)
    - Ceremony in Spain (Box 8)
    - Convention Photos, post-SCW (Box 8)
    - Convention Photos, Post-SCW + Negatives (Box 8)
    - Dance/Performance [?] (Box 8)
    - 'David' Sketch Model with Scale Figure (Box 8)
    - Dinner, Catalan Assocation of Former Political Prisoners (Box 8)
    - Dinner Banquet, Douglas Jacoba, Ludwig Renan, and others (Box 8)
    - Dinner in Spain, Post-SCW (Box 8)
    - "Fredericka Martin Papers" Plaque (Box 8)
    - Gatherings (Box 8)
    - Group Photos/Banquets: William Allander, Jake Kramer of VALB (Box 8)
    - IB & SCW Monuments (Box 8)
    - IB in Spain, photos by George Sossenko, October 2000 (Box 8)
    - IB Memorial (2005) - Photos by Antonio Vilella Valles (Box 8)
    - IB Reunion (Moscow) (Box 8)
    - Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order of the International Workers Order (Pinelawn, NY Memorial) (Box 8)
    - "La Mano" Sculpture - Stockholm, Sweden (Box 8)
    - Lincoln Vets on a Visit to Nicaragua (Box 8)
    - Monument & Banner (plus photo fragment - unidentified corner) (Box 8)
    - Ossie Davis and Ruby Dee at NY Dinner, Speaking (Box 8)
    - Outdoor Memorial (and Negative Copies) (Box 8)
    - Plaques (Box 8)
    - Rallies and Banquets: Howard Da Sylvia and Paul Roebson Jr. speaking (Box 8)
    - Post-SCW in Park and at Lakehouse (Box 8)
    - Reunion, Banquet, Performance (Box 8)
    - Reunion, photos by Antonio Vilella Valles (Box 8)
    - SCW and IB Monuments and Memorials (Box 8)
    - Sidney Rosenstein Plaque (Box 8)
    - Spain, near Ebro (May 1991) (Box 8)
    - Speaking at a Dinner Banquet (Box 8)
    - Tower Hamlets Memorial in London (April 13, 1916) (Box 8)
    - Unidentified Individuals at Banquet (Box 8)
    - VALB (Box 8)
    - VALB (and Negatives) (Box 8)
    - VALB Anniversary & PCE Photos + Negatives from Robert Merriman Collection (Box 8)
    - VALB Event (photos from Connie Hogarth sent to Moe Fishman) (Box 8)
    - VALB: Reunions in Spain and USA (mostly-1980s) (Box 8)
    - Wolff, Milton; Dolores Ibarruri, Sep 1938 - Oct 1938 (Box 8)
  - Subseries IV:F: Posters, Postcards, Pamphlets, Paintings
    - Bombing of Guernica (Box 8)
    - Ed Binder: Photographs of Post Exhibit for SF Bay Area Post (Box 8)
    - Exhibit Layout/Display Photos (Box 8)
    - Exhibit Photos: Posters/Propaganda (French) (Box 8)
    - Individual Portraits and Postcards (Box 8)
    - Guernica Postcards and Negatives (Box 8)
    - Murals and Posters (Box 8)
    - Painting of Aviator (Box 8)
    - Dr. Edward Barsky, Photos from Milt Wolff Bancroft Library at Berkeley, CA, 1985 (Box 8)
    - Photographs of Artwork (Box 8)
    - Photographs of Posters (Box 9)
    - Photographs of Posters (Box 9)
    - Postcards of Francisco Franco (Box 9)
    - Posters and Magazine Clippings (Box 9)
    - Posters & Postcards (Box 9)
    - Posters & Postcards (Box 9)
    - Posters and Postcards SCW (Box 9)
    - Posters Project (1977) (Negatives and Negative Copies) (Box 9)
    - Posters and Propaganda (Box 9)
    - Posters: Negative Copies (Box 9)
    - Posters on Foreign Intervention in SCW (Box 9)
    - Posters: Spanish Republic (Box 9)
    - Propaganda (Box 9)
    - Propaganda (Box 9)
    - Propaganda (Box 9)
    - Propaganda (Box 9)
    - Proof of Italian Intervention (Box 9)
    - "The Return" by Robert Coane - 50th Reunion Trip to Spain (Box 9)
    - SCW Postcards (Box 9)
    - SCW Printed Ephemera (Box 9)
    - SCW Prints: Martinez de Leon (Box 9)
  - Subseries IV:G: General Pt. II
    - Prisoners (Box 9)
    - Prisoners (Box 9)
    - Americans Captured by Franco Return to New York, 1939 (Box 9)
    - Italians (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Barcelona's Ramblas + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Color Photos (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Falset to Gandesa (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Franco Demonstration Fair + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Gandesa + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Madrid + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Marca Mora to Corbera + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Negatives (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Rome Graffiti Fair (Color + Negative) (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Sardana - Barcelona: Carts to Ualls (Box 9)
    - Return Trips to Spain: Unknown City Photos (Black & White) [Barcelona?] (Box 9)
    - Sailors/Ships, SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Soldiers in Spain [more info in VF?] (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Al Warren Photos sent to Danny Collums + Negatives (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Battlefront (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: And Civilians (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: And Civilians (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Cohen, MacKenzie Papineau, Transport, Tereul Front (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Contact Sheet: SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Contact Sheet: SCW Battlefront (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: David Smith, Martin Hourihan, Jerry Weinberg, -- Rosenstein, Frederick Krumpeck, Harry Mack, Ruby Ryants, Kurt Bevense, Sid Levine, -- Mendez, Saul Friedberg, Norman Perlmon (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: DeWitt Parker [aka Eric], Unidentified, Major Johnson (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Dr. Barsky and Others (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: E. Browder, J. North, S. Wellman, Bob Minor, and others unidentified (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Ed Lending and others (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Earl Browder, MacKenzie Papineau Battalion, Sanitation, Castro, Peters, Jarama, Russian Tanks, etc. (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Free Time (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Group Photo (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: International Brigadiers from Japan, USA, Cuba, Phillipines, Chile & Trench Photo (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: International Volunteers and Daily Activities (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Jack Klein, Hugh Slater, Ernest Hemingway (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Joe Stone and Sam Stone (Washington Battalion), Jul 1937 (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: John Murra, Dave Smith, Henry Moch, Nain Perline, Fedorovick, Ernie Parlour, Gabriel Luimmones, Sam Mann (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Ken Graeber, Ed Lending, Jack Shafran (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Max (Mac) Binn, Joe Baron, Len Spencer, Pete Smith, Ken Graber, Roy Braden, Jack Hartzman, Dachecko, Harold Smith, Robert Nagle, Phil Muller, Priczbilski, Paul Robeson, Karl Deutstler, Dr. Edward K. Barsky + Others (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Marching (Ernie Amatarck, Al Tanz, Ben Sills, Ed Lending, Harry Schoenfeld, Larry Cane) (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Mihaily Szalvay "Chapaiev", Gabriel Fort, Frei Copeman, Hans Klaus, Harry Haywood, Vladimir Copic, Prodon "Petur", Todorov Tabakov, Janos Galicz "Gal", George Aitken, Ales Bebler, Martin Hourihan, Steve Nelson, Mirko Markovic, Dave Mates (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Military Parades and Demonstrations (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Milton Epstein, Peter Frye, Vincent Lossowski, Ed Lending George Watt, -- Payne, Larry Maynard, Colm Haber, Sam Schiff, Joe Taylor (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Officers of the Dimitrov A.A. Battery (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: On the Battlefront (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: On the Battlefront (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: On the Battlefront (Ed Lending, Jack Shafran, Norman Berkowitz) (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Pat Reid, Morris Breier, Harry Fisher (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Paul Burns Photos from Jarama Valley / Front (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Polish Volunteers (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Ralph Thornton, Santiago Alvarez, Major Alan Johnson, Emile Jacobs, Harry Fisher, Ed Lending, Claude Pringle, Bill Frame, other unidentified individuals (includes negatives) (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Robert Capa SCW Photos (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Saul Newton Photos, includes battlefront (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW Militias (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW, Officers and Community Organization and Planning (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: SCW, Portrait, Negative Copies + Portrait Negative (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Unidentified (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Unidentified Officers (Box 9)
    - Soldiers: Walter Kolowski Photos and negative (Box 9)
    - Women: Life during the SCW (Box 9)
    - Women: SCW (Box 9)
    - Women: SCW (Contact Sheet) (Box 9)
    - Women: SCW: Reunion in Spain, 1977 (Box 9)
    - Women: Workers (Box 9)
    - Women: Workers in Spain (Box 9)
    - Victims: 13 Year Old Moorish Boy, Hospital in Madrid (Box 9)
    - Victims: Casualties (Box 9)
    - Victims: Children Refugees of SCW (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees (Box 9)
    - Victims: Refugees and "The Good Fight" Promo Photos (1984) (Box 9)
    - Victims: SCW (Box 9)
    - Victims: SCW Casualties (Box 9)
    - Victims: SCW: Wounded, Orphans, Dead in Hospitals (Box 9)
    - Victims: Women and Children (Box 9)
  - Subseries IV:H: Processed, Photographs Not Integrated
    - Action Scene, Soldiers Shoot Uphill (P. 592) (Box 10)
    - Aerial View of VALB Banner Bearers (P. 677) (Box 10)
    - Anniversary Dinner: General [Including Steve Nelson and Paul Robeson, Jr.], Undated (Box 10)
    - Anti-Aircraft Machine Gun on Train (P. 384) (Box 10)
    - At the Front: Non-Combat (Box 10)
    - Board commemorating the unity of an "independent" Spain (P. 828) (Box 10)
    - Boxing Match (P. 371) (Box 10)
    - Bus Taking Veterans Home (P. 350) (Box 10)
    - Cannons and Other Materials Seized From the Italians (P. 583) (Box 10)
    - Detail of Figure Holding Sword, Berlin, East Germany (P. 906) (Box 10)
    - Fallen Utility Pole (P. 632) (Box 10)
    - Fire in the distance across Spanish landscape (P. 688) (Box 10)
    - Demonstrations/Events: In Spain (Box 10)
    - Dicks, Walter (Separated from ALBA 143) (Box 10)
    - Dry River Bed (P. 1116) (Box 10)
    - Fiesta del Libro (P. 527) (Box 10)
    - Gibbs, Theodore (Separated from ALBA 143) (Box 10)
    - House in the Woods [Spain?] (P. 1143) (Box 10)
    - Interior of Bombed House (P. 893) (Box 10)
    - Italian Anti-Fascists, Undated (Box 10)
    - Leisure: Reading (Box 10)
    - Liberty Bell Fiesta, "Jitterbug Jamboree," Royal Windsor (P. 535), Dec 10, 1938 (Box 10)
    - Lincoln Brigade Members on Road to Saragossa, about 15km away from bombed Madrid (P. 608) (Box 10)
    - Long John Radio Program (P. 653), March 1962 (Box 10)
    - Magazine Pictures Depicting Horrors of Franco's Spain (P. 900) (Box 10)
    - Making a Camp Kitchen, Cleaning Vegetables (P. 633) (Box 10)
    - Medallion: "Por la libertad, la Independencia, y la Democracia," (Mexico 1969) (P. 908) (Box 10)
    - Meeting of Political Commisar of 15th Internation Brigade with Luigi Gallo (P. 344), Mar 1938 (Box 10)
    - Miss [Yukon or Yurilon ?] Ayuda America (P. 1073) (Box 10)
    - New York: VALB Parade, [1980s] (Box 10)
    - Pack Horse in Hilly Spanish Terrain (P. 847) (Box 10)
    - Photo of Scrawled Poster Calling for Mass Meeting at "MAIN HALL" (P. 880), Apr 22, 1937 (Box 10)
    - Photographs (Samuel Krafsar) [from ALBA 267), circa 1950; 1960 (Box 10)
    - Popular Front Supporters March Through Village Streets (P. 905) (Box 10)
    - Portrait in Small Circular Frame (P. 1127) (Box 10)
    - Proofsheet strips: Battlefield (Box 10)
    - Proofsheet Strips: Train (Box 10)
    - Rally/Concert at Bandshell (P. 644) (Box 10)
    - Reeves, Otto (Separated from ALBA 143) (Box 10)
    - Renau Painting: Handshake/Solidarity with the Spanish Republic (P. 902) (Box 10)
    - Restaurant Interior (P. 842) (Box 10)
    - Sea Plane on the Waterway (P. 849) (Box 10)
    - Shower closeup... (P. 362) (Box 10)
    - Southern Front (P. 846) (Box 10)
    - Spanish Cities and Street Scenes, ca. 1936-1937 (Box 10)
    - Thousands of Berliners Gather at Lustgarten to Demonstrate against Fascism (P. 822), Sep 11, 1966 (Box 10)
    - Truck on Railroad Car (P. 925) (Box 10)
    - VALB 20th Anniversary Celebration (P. 844) (Box 10)
    - Veterans Banner Leads Car and Parade through Street (P. 897) (Box 10)